Let's delve into change and configuration
management in a little more detail.
So remember, change is a hot button.
We want to understand the change control
process.
Remember, changes won't just happen
Willy-nilly on our projects.
So it's important that we properly control
all changes to our project.
And I've mentioned this over and over,
prevent unnecessary changes.
We also want to prevent scope creep.
That's adding to the
scope without giving us the
time, the money, the
resources needed to do so.
That's a big no-no.
And we need to prevent goal plating.
So that's a form of scope creep where
someone in the performing organization
decides to add some bells and whistles,
some features that were not already agreed
upon, meaning within the scope baseline
that's a huge no-no all right and if
you're working on government contracts
that can even be considered bribery so we
do not add any more or less than the scope
agreed upon all right on predictive
projects remember these are traditional
deliverables are usually fixed.
Changes are strictly controlled.
Whereas agile, you are expecting change.
We'll discover, explore the requirements
along the way.
So you can't control that.
That is something we adapt to.
We know change is coming.
All right.
So the change management plan,
remember, that is created in the very
beginning when we develop the project
management plan.
I have a small window.
That's why I'm doing it really smallly.
So remember, when we start developing the
project management plan, the border of our
puzzle, change and configuration
management plans are created immediately.
So the change management
plan, let's go into detail,
documents all procedures
regarding change control.
How changes will be made and controlled.
It identifies the authority levels for who
can approve changes or reject them.
It identifies members of the CCB.
If there's not a CCB, the sponsor has
authority to approve or reject changes.
An authority could be external like a
government agency.
It will also outline the
roles and responsibilities of
the CCB and the project
manager regarding change control.
So usually, and I have mentioned this
before, usually the the PM can approve
corrective and preventive action since it
normally is not affecting a baseline.
So keep that in mind.
Corrective action, something is wrong.
We're getting trying to
get back in alignment with
our plan what was agreed
upon in the first place.
Like we're spending too much, we're taking
too long.
Whereas preventive action, these are all
through change requests.
Preventive action, something has already
happened.
We want to make a
change right now to stay in
alignment with the
plan, not get off track.
The last one is defect repair.
So defect repair, we have a non-conforming
product or component
that needs to be fixed.
Typically tangible, something tangible.
Let's say we're supposed to create
markers.
so if any piece of this the lid is
supposed to fit on here the top or the
bottom it's supposed to be a straight
little pointy tip versus you know slanted
if any piece of this does not work that is
called a defect non-conforming product or
component so it has to be
repaired so i don't remember whether
or not i went into that in
enough detail with when I talked
about performing
integrated change control.
These are the reasons for change requests.
Preventive action, corrective action,
defect repair, and adding or deleting scope.
So keep that in mind.
All right.
Now configuration management
details how versions,
plans, baselines, documents
will be made and controlled.
The details.
So the big thing to remember this is your
version control to always make sure we're
working from the latest plans documents
baselines versions the three components of
the configuration management system will
be the identification status accounting
and verification and audit a little more
than you really need to um know for the
exam so version control think version
control and So if we're in the middle of
our project, we're executing and that
house rento tearing out the tub,
found out there wasn't that water vapor
barrier.
Now there's mold and all the walls and the
structural beams have been eaten away.
All right.
So you have to have a change request.
The scope has to change, which will affect
plans, baselines, and other documents,
resources, costs.
We cannot now work from a previous plan.
It is no longer valid.
So configuration management
will always make sure we're
working from the latest
plans, documents, versions.
The old ones archived, we now work from
the latest.
That's version control, configuration
management.